Breymer Yesit Robles Caro

Personal Information:

Cellphone: +57 3015864738

Email:byrobles2009@gmail.com

Skype: breyner.robles

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/breymer-yesit-robles-caro-b111a335/

Professional Card: 08255-258986 ATL

Career Summary

Senior software designer with nine years of experience in the development of multi-tier database-driven systems and multi-client service-oriented applications with rich UI. Thorough understanding of technologies and Development Lifecycle. Scrum methodology and using JEE architecture, frameworks Spring, JSF, Primefaces, and Angular as well as design patterns. He's worked as a technical leader at Gonet S.A, projects with the Unit Land Restitution (URT) and Technology Ministry (Mintic) in Colombia. As a professional in Java EE platforms and robust transactional products, I've had opportunities to work with technologies and tools for designing and implementing enterprise computing solutions using different styles (Web-based, CMS Portals, ETL Solutions, Desktop Apps, SOA Platforms, Middleware Services, Microservices Solution, Caching and Grid Solutions, SPA Sites), participating in software construction cycle for stages related to project planning and delivery cycles, requirements gathering, architecture design, implementation, and production promotions (production deployment cycle) Through my experience, I can say my skills focus on following professional profiles:

- Java Architect.
- TL Project Leader
- Architecture components designer.
- Applications developer

Summary of Qualifications

Skills:

- Java EE
- Java SE
- JSF
- Prime Faces
- Rich Faces
- ICE Faces
- ADF
- JavaScript
- JQuery
- AngularJS
- Angular

- HTML5
- Bootstrap
- Rest
- SOAP
- SQL
- JPA
- JPQL
- Hibernate
- Gradle
- Maven
- Spring framework

- Spring boot
- Spring Integration
- Spring cloud
- HQL
- MVC
- SOA
- 00P
- Design Patterns
- PostgreSQL
- Oracle
- PL/SQL

- MySQL
- Jenkins
- Azure DevOps
- Docker
- Kubernetes
- AWS
- GCP

- Azure
- Scrum
- RUP
- UML
- GIT
- SVN
- JIRA

- Cluster setup
- Load Balancers
- Software Security
- Software Architecture
- Team Coaching

Languages

- Spanish (native speaker)
- English(Intermediate)

Career History

EPAM, Bogota, Colombia Senior backend engineer

March. 2022 - Actual

- Application architecture solution. Building software components design, Integrate the application with external vendors, configuration and creation of Rest Api and document it using swagger.
- Apps Implementation using Spring frameworks
- Building POCs to validate implementations.
- Using Gradle For Generating environments.
- Java 17 Project

BLANC LABS, Bogotá, Colombia Full stack Senior software engineer

Sept. 2020 - March 2022

- •Application architecture definition for middleware solutions, guidelines, strategies implementation for solutions based on Java for Equitable Bank. Software components design under architectural procedures and standards established, propose strategies, technologies, and methodologies to improve delivery times and simplify software construction processes, serve and support projects
- Apps Implementation using Spring frameworks
- Coordinating the team does deliver tasks in the Sprint
- Building POCs to validate implementations.
- Using Gradle For Generating environments.
- Front End adjustment to EQB app using Angular Version 8

GLOBANT, Bogotá, Colombia Java Senior developer and Software designer

March. 2016 - September. 2020

 Application architecture definition for middleware solutions, guidelines, strategies implementation for solutions based on Java for SOUTHWEST AIRLINES, Software components design under architectural procedures and standards established, propose strategies, technologies, and methodologies to improve delivery times and simplify software construction processes, serve and support Project Managers in matters concerning to technical domain. Lead development teams located in Bogotá (Colombia), support, and guide the team to ensure consistency for software under development according to architectural guidelines. Strategic planning for deliveries, backlog management, and release planning by using agile methodologies. Technical Coaching for teams (Kepler POD) Administration for agile resources using Atlassian stack: Jira, Confluence, and BitBucket

- Apps Implementation using Spring frameworks
- Coordinating the team does deliver tasks in the Sprint
- Building POCs to validate implementations.
- Using Gradle For Generating environments.
- Define Architecture for OEW Projects

GONET COLOMBIA S.A, Bogotá, Colombia Aug. 2013 – Feb. 2016

Technical Leader JAVA at Project e-biller Sep. 2015 – Feb. 2016 ● Definition's architecture based on JEE

- Implementation using frameworks Spring and JSF
- Libraries creator of exporting and importing a file
- Developer by some functionalities.

Senior Software Developer JAVA at Project URT Oct. 2014 – Aug. 2015 • Developer by several functionalities for project

Senior Software Developer JAVA at Project Monitoring Tools Aug. 2013 − Sep. 2014 • Developer by several functionalities for project

DELAWARE CONSULTORÍA COLOMBIA S.A Bogotá, Colombia Mar. 2013 – Aug. 2013

Senior Analyst Developer JAVA

PANDORA IT S.A Bogotá, Colombia Aug. 2010 – Feb. 2013

Senior Analyst developer JAVA at Project ELYON

- Definition's architecture based on JEE
- Implementation using frameworks JSF
- Developer by some functionalities.

Education

Simón Bolívar University, Barranquilla, Colombia Jan. 2004 – Jul. 2009 BS, Systems Engineering **SimónBolívarUniversity**, Barranquilla, Colombia Jan. 2009–Jul. 2009 WebEngineeringCertificate **OracleUniversity**, Oct. 2015–Oct. 2015 OracleCertifiedAssociate, JAVA SE8 Programmer